thelawpages.com 2019-04-06

# thelawpages.com© Contact Form

## Preamble

This Privacy Policy sets out the approach taken by thelawpages.com Ltd ("thelawpages.com" "We", "Us", "Our") to the personal information of its subscribers and visitors to its web-site ("You", "Your"). By using and visiting our website and using our service You agree to this privacy policy. Privacy and confidentiality are at the heart of our service. We respect your privacy - our service depends on treating personal information in confidence and with sensitivity. thelawpages.com will only record your personal data as set out in this policy. We will not sell or trade any of Your identifiable personal information. 

## What information do We collect and why?

Thelawpages.com may need to take personal data from You (including your name and email) where this is necessary to communicate with you. You will have a choice whether to give this information to us or not. You can view and control all the information we have for you online and update or remove the information. We will only use this information to communicate with you in accordance with the policy.

We will not use or disclose your personal information given to us for communication with you for any other purpose.

The Site offers a recruitment service. We will only provide information, offers and services that may be of interest to You where you have given your unambiguous consent. We will always disclose to you the type of information we collect. The Site will also provide links to a range of third party Sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

**Legal basis for processing**

The Legal basis for processing is our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection Regulation), the wider public interest on the principles of Open Justice and the administration of justice (Criminal Proceedure Rules). 

TheLawPages.Com serve legal professionals, the media and the public under the principles of Open Justice. We provide a professionals directory, Crown and High Court Lists and a Criminal Sentences Tool.

**Court Lists**

TheLawPages publishes 'Court lists' which gives the date, court name, case number and defendants name. For a full court list journalists should contact the court to obtain information including the defendants date of birth, current address and details of the charges against them. This information is disclosed to journalists to ensure the accurate identification of a defendant (even where it is not presented in open court). 

Users of TheLawPages.Com have a legitimate interest which justifies the continued availability of court list data (See Criminal Procedure Rules). The court list data is placed on a public notice board and open to public inspection. Court hearings may be listed over several years. The court list data on TheLawPages.Com can be browsed for the previous 6 months and searched for a year. We do not allow search engines to serve cached version of the court lists. 

There is a reasonable expectation that the defendants name would appear on the court lists. The information is factual and defendants are innocent until proven guilty. 

Archives of the court lists, including indictments (where resporting restictions do not apply), may be available on The National Archives - http://www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/help-with-your-research/research-guides/criminal-courts-england-wales-from-1972/ - and on other websites (including courtserve.net) which are not controlled by us. 

**Sentences Tool**

We provide some court case results - information linking [criminal offences](https://www.thelawpages.com/criminal-offence/criminal-offences.php), [defendants](https://www.thelawpages.com/court-cases/ "Find Criminal Defendants"), [barristers](https://www.thelawpages.com/legal-directory/barristers-3-criminal-barristers-9.php "criminal barristers"), [solicitors](https://www.thelawpages.com/legal-directory/criminal-law-firms-1-criminal-solicitors-9.php "criminal solicitors") and [judges](https://www.thelawpages.com/court-cases/ "Search Judges") \- to further Open Justice - 'Justice Seen, Justice Done'. 

**Right to be forgotton**

We anonymise data when a sentence is spent ([The Rehabilitation of Offenders Act 1974](https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1974/53 "Rehabilitation of Offenders Act 1974")).

We consider all requests for removal, especially where an individual might be identified due to an unusual name and there are concerns there is a negative effect on that individual or it would cause them unwarranted harm. 

**Children and sensitive personal information**

There are automatic reporting restrictions on the names of minors and we do not collect sensitive personal information. 

### Use of cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work (Strictly Necessary or Essential), or work more efficiently (Functional or Performance), as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Cookies are used on Our website to perform essential tasks, for performance, for analytical statistics and to secure data.

The table below explains the cookies we use and why. 

## Cookie

| 

## Name

| 

## Purpose

| 

## More information  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz

| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | 

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.   
  
The Law Pages site terms and cookie policy acceptance | 

TLP_agree_tc

| This cookie is used to record if a user has accepted the use of cookies on the ICO website. | 

This cookie will expire in 1 year.   
  
Session cookie | 

PHPSESSID

| 

A session cookie - used to keep track of when your session is started/ended.This cookie is essential for the online search forms to operate. This cookie is used to identify You as a user between page loads. This allows Us to remember certain settings, like which part of the website you were using before you were asked to sign in or register. These cookies are strictly necessary to enable you to move about the site or to provide certain features you have requested.

| 

This cookie is deleted when you close your browser.  
  
Content Management System cookie | 

OAID

| 

A persistent cookie - This cookie is set by our content management system to track banner click activity for analytical purposes.This cookie will expire in 1 year.

| 

The supplier of our content management system (the software we use to update our website) is working to remove this cookie from their product.  
  
Functional cookies | cookid  
cookname  
pane  
drop down  
droppedin  
legaladvicetabs  
acgroupswithpersist  
acopendivids  
submenuheader  
survey  
| These cookies are used to remember the states of graphical menus users have selected to aid navigation of the website. If you do not share your computer and select the 'remember me' option when you sign into the website, a cookie will facilitate this functionality. | [](http://www.workcast.co.uk/privacy.aspx "External link")  
  
Third Party Social Media Cookies: addthis.com  
linkedin.com  
twitter.com  
facebook.com  
plus.google.com  
youtube.com

| 

Theses may include: 

__atuvc  
X-LI-IDC  

| 

A persistent cookie - used to track banner click activity for Social Media purposes.

Third Party Advertising Cookies  | 

Theses may include: 

flashtalking.com  
Mediaplex.com  | 

A persistent cookie - used to track banner click activity for analytical purposes.

**  How can I manage the use of cookies on this website?**

All browser technologies enable you to manage the cookies in the cookie folder of your web browser. This means that you can either delete cookies from your cookie folder once you have finished your visit at our website or you can set your preferences with regard to the use of cookies before you begin browsing our website. Please note that deleting or rejecting cookies may adversely affect your user experience of our website.

You can find out further information at:

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [http://www.wikihow.com/Clear-Your-Browsers-Cookies](http://www.wikihow.com/Clear-Your-Browser%27s-Cookies).

## Disclosure of personal information

We will not disclose personal data without consent. Your personal information will only be disclosed where we are obliged or permitted by law to do so. 

## Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. 

## E-mail Communications

We do not sell or rent out Your e-mail addresses to third parties for unsolicited e-mail communications. 

## Security

We use privacy-by-design practices, encryption and authentication tools to protect your sensitive personal information. We will never willfully disclose Your individually identifiable data to any third party in breach of this Privacy Policy. 

## Data Protection Legislation

We are the data controller for purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and Data Protection Act 1998 ( Registration number Z253853X. http://www.ico.gov.uk/) 

## Your Rights

You can request to access, update or correct your personal information. You also have the right to object to direct marketing. You can access the request process [here](https://www.thelawpages.com/contactus.php?option=1).

You may have additional rights pursuant to your local law applicable to the processing. For example, if the processing of your personal information is subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), and your personal information is processed based on legitimate interests, you have the right to object to the processing on grounds relating to your specific situation. Under GDPR you may also have the right to request to have your personal information deleted or restricted and ask for portability of your personal information.

## Right to Lodge a Complaint

In the event you consider our processing of your personal information not to be compliant with the applicable data protection laws, you can lodge a complaint:

  * Directly with TheLawPages.Com by using [this form](https://www.thelawpages.com/contactus.php?option=1). or write to us: Fortescue House, Court St, Trowbridge BA14 8FA
  * With the competent data protection authority - [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/). The name and contact details of the Data Protection Authorities in the European Union can be found [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

## Changes to this privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This privacy notice was last updated on 23 May 2018.
